Sajad Jazayeri

☑ sajad.jazayeri@gmail.com ☐ (813)362-9299

HIGHLIGHTS

A highly skilled self-motivated geophysicist with a PhD in Geology, creative, innovative and independent thinker and multitasking team player with a strong background in **programming**, **signal processing**, **Geophysical data analysis**, **Modelling and Inversion**, quantitative interpretation, **Artificial Intelligence** (AI) and Machine Learning (ML). I also have 5 years of industry experience.

CORE SKILLS

- Management: Solution-oriented, Independent, Time-delivery, Decisive, Disciplined, Structured,
 Objective prioritizing
- Geophysics: Exploration Seismology, Electromagnetics (EM), Ground Penetrating Radar (GPR), gravity, Magnetic, Electrical Resistivity, GPS
- Modelling: 2D and 3D modelling, Inversion, Imaging, Velocity structure modelling, full-waveform inversion (FWI), attribute analysis
- o **Software**: Geosoft Oasis Montaj, AarhusINV, Aarhus workbench, ArcGIS, PEST, SMT Kingdom Suite, Global Mapper, Hampson Russel
- o Programming: MATLAB, Python, R, P5
- **Relevant courses**: Potential field data processing, Optimization, Project management, Statistical data mining, Basic programming in UNIX systems, Web design using HTML

EDUCATION

University of Tehran

University of South Florida

Tampa, FL May 2019

PhD in Geophysics. GPA: 3.64/4, Thesis: FWI of high-frequency electromagnetic GPR data

Tehran, Iran

MSc in Geophysics. GPA: 16.63/20, Thesis: 3D Geomagnetic data modelling

August 2009

Razi University

Kermanshah, Iran

BSc in Physics, solid state. GPA: 16.12/20 August 2007

EMPLOYMENT AND RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

School of Geosciences, University of South Florida

Tampa, FL

Graduate Assistant

August 2014 - Present

- Developed modelling and inversion codes for time-series data. The established full-waveform inversion method improves subsurface model resolution by 78%.
- o Developed a full-waveform inversion software package for surface GPR data
- Created a Sparse blind deconvolution for noise reduction and source wavelet optimization of electromagnetic and seismic signals
- o Modelled and Inverted Airborne Electromagnetic data (AEM) for earth modelling
- Extensive data analysis, modelling and interpretation of EM, Electrical resistivity, Gravity, magnetic, LiDAR and GPS data
- Developed machine learning algorithms for automatic anomaly detection, using Power Spectral Density (PSD) and Dynamic Time Warping (DTW)

Kian Rayan Co. Tehran, Iran

Research Geophysicist

August 2012 - August 2014

- Established and developed new data processing codes and platforms resulting in average 60% decrease in data processing required-time
- Developed and restructured customer software training program and presented it to 12 different customer firms, resulting in a 85% increase in customer satisfaction levels
- o Performed code performance evaluation and debugged the codes
- o Presented research results in two expositions resulting in 18% costumer increase

Geophysicist

September 2009 - August 2012

- Processed and modelled geophysical data (reflection and refraction Seismic, prestack and poststack seismic data, Magnetics, EM, GPR and MT)
- o Interpreted and analyzed different data and prepared reports

Institute of Geophysics, University of Tehran

Tehran, Iran

Research Assistant

December 2008 - August 2009

o Potential field data modelling at Semnan basin (sponsored by the National Iranian Oil Company, NIOC)

Geological Survey and Mineral Exploration of Iran

Tehran, Iran

Intern

October 2008 - December 2008

- o Processed the data of two actual projects under supervision of a senior geophysicist and prepared reports
- o Communicated with principal geophysicists and team leaders to identify the instrumentation gaps and needs

SELECTED AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- o 2019 Richard A. Davis, Jr. (RAD) Endowed Fellowship in Geology Research, USF
- 2018 Dissertation completion Fellowship, USF Office of Graduate Studies
- o 2017 Recognized as one of the top presented 39 papers in SEG annual meeting 2017, Houston, TX
- o 2017 American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE) Trent Dames and William Moore Fellowship
- o 2015, 2016, 2018 USF School of Geosciences Tharp Research Fellowship, USF
- o 2015 Sigma Xi GIAR (Grants-in-Aid of Research) award
- o 2009 National Iranian Oil Company Graduate Research Fellowship

LEADERSHIP AND INVOLVEMENT

- o Technical program committee member, SEG 2018 Annual meeting, Anaheim, CA
- o Member of SEG near surface technical session leadership board and Media Leader (since 2017)
- o President of the Iranian Student Association at USF (2017-2018)
- o Co-organizer and primary chair for multiple sessions at AGU and SEG meetings since 2017
- o Journal reviewer: Geophysics; The Leading Edge; Near Surface Geophysics; Journal of Geophysics and Engineering; Journal of Environmental & Engineering Geophysics, Remote Sensing; Journal of Applied Geophysics; International Journal of Speleology; Arabian Journal of Geosciences. Conference reviewer: SEG annual meetings (since 2017), AGU (since 2017), IEEE (2018)

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- 1. **S. Jazayeri**, N. Kazemi, S. Kruse. (2019). Sparse Blind Deconvolution of Ground Penetrating Radar data. In: IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote Sensing. DOI: 10.1109/TGRS.2018.2886741
- 2. **S. Jazayeri**, A. Saghafi, S. Esmaeili, C.P. Tsokos. (2019). Online Object Detection using Dynamic Time Warping on Common-Offset Ground Penetrating Radar. In: Expert Systems With Applications, Elsevier, Vol. 122, pp. 102-107. DOI: 10.1016/j.eswa.2018.12.057
- 3. A. Saghafi, **S. Jazayeri**, S. Esmaeili, C. Tsokos. (2019). Power Spectral Density to Radar online Object Detection In: Structural Control and Health Monitoring, Elsevier, DOI: 10.1002/stc.2354.
- 4. **S. Jazayeri**, A. Klotzsche and S. Kruse. (2018). Improved resolution of pipes with full waveform inversion of common-offset GPR data using PEST. In: Geophysics, 83(4), H27-H41.
- 5. S., Kruse, **S. Jazayeri**. (2016). Evaluating potential benefits of improved understanding of uncertainties associated with airborne electromagnetic (AEM) data in Eastern Nebraska. 101 pp.

PATENTS

- 1. **S., Jazayeri**, S., Kruse. (2019). Precise Infrastructure Mapping Using Full-Waveform Inversion of Radar Signals. Filed Jun 27, 2018, United States Patent and Trademark Office, Non-Provisional patent number: 10,234,552 (Granted on Mar 19 2019).
- 2. A., Saghafi, **S. Jazayeri**, S., Esmaeili, C. Tsokos. (2019). Systems and Methods For Detecting Buried Objects. Filed Jun 28, 2018, United States Patent and Trademark Office, Non-Provisional patent number: 10,175,350 (Granted on Jan 8 2019)